Guide to the McCoy-Love Family Papers, 1774-1970 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
McCoy-Love Family papers 1774-1970 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
McCoy-Love family
12.3 Linear Feet circa 9,210 Items
Asheville, N.C. residents.
Two prominent members of the families were George William McCoy, Sr. (b. 1901), editor of the Asheville-Citizen Times, and his father-in-law, Harry Weaver Love (b. 1883), YMCA executive. The collection contains personal and business correspondence, genealogical material, financial and legal records, printed material, clippings, addresses and writings, scrapbooks, miscellaneous items, photographs, and a number of volumes. Topics include the Great Smoky Mountains National Park, and the Thomas Wolfe Memorial Assoc. Harry Love's business papers include a large number of correspondence, reports, pictures and volumes relating to his work with the YMCA, in the U.S. and abroad; there are a great many items relating to the Philippine Islands. There are a sizable number of papers from Wythe Munford Peyton, a civil and highway engineer, who worked for several N.C. railroads; the papers of William C. Coleman, a businessman who sold and serviced Harley-Davidson motorcycles (1914-1915); and papers of the Frelinghuysen-Southwick family of N.J. and N.Y., one relative being a Senator and another, Emeline Sherman Smith, a poet. There are a few items concerning Thomas Dixon who founded the Mt. Mitchell Assoc. of Arts and Sciences.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The McCoy-Love Family Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1980 and 1986.
Collection Overview
The papers of this Asheville, North Carolina family span the years 1774-1970. Two prominent members of the families were George William McCoy, Sr. (b. 1901), editor of the Asheville-Citizen Times, and his father-in-law, Harry Weaver Love (b. 1883), YMCA executive. The collection contains personal and business correspondence, genealogical material, financial and legal records, printed material, clippings, addresses and writings, scrapbooks, miscellaneous items, photographs, and a number of volumes. Topics include the development of parks in the Appalachia region, particularly the Great Smoky Mountains National Park, and activities relating to the Thomas Wolfe Memorial Association. Harry Love's business papers include a large number of correspondence, reports, pictures and volumes relating to his work with the YMCA, in the U.S. and abroad; there are a great many items relating to the Philippine Islands. There is a sizable number of papers from Wythe Munford Peyton, a civil and highway engineer, who worked for several N.C. railroads; the papers of William C. Coleman, a businessman who sold and serviced Harley-Davidson motorcycles (1914-1915); and papers of the Frelinghuysen-Southwick family of N.J. and N.Y., one relative being a Senator and another, Emeline Sherman Smith, a poet. There are a few items concerning Thomas Dixon who founded the Mt. Mitchell Assoc. of Arts and Sciences.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
McCoy family (N.C.)
Love family (N.C.)
McCoy, George William
Love, Harry Weaver
Peyton, Wythe Munford
Coleman, William C.
Frelinghuysen-Southwick family
Young Men's Christian Association
Asheville-Citizen Times (newspaper)
Businessmen -- North Carolina -- Correspondence
Thomas Wolfe Memorial Association
United States. Great Smoky Mountains National Park
North Carolina -- Economic conditions
North Carolina -- Civil engineering
North Carolina -- Railroads
Philippines
Scrapbooks
Photograph albums
Photographs
Contents of Collection
- Biographical Information Series, 1904-1963, (2 boxes)
  - Genealogy, 1926-1954 (Box 1)
  - Information Folder (Box 29)
  - Biographical Information
    - McCoy, George William, 1923-1954
    - Love, Harry Weaver, 1904-1960
    - Peyton, Wythe Munford, 1911-1963
- Legal Papers Series, 1774-1964, (1 box)
  - 1774-1964 (Box 1)
- Financial Papers Series, 1885-1954, (1 box)
  - Miscellaneous, 1885-1952 (Box 2)
  - YMCA, 1918-1922
  - Thomas Wolfe Memorial Association, 1949-1954
  - Financial accounts, specifications, etc. for roads, railroads and other enterprises, 1908-1919
- Miscellaneous Papers Series, 1860-1961 and undated, (4 boxes)
  - YMCA (Box 3)
    - U.S., 1910-1924
    - Philippine Islands, 1900-1921
    - China and Chinese branch in the Philippines, 1920
    - Latin America, 1921 and undated
  - General, 1860-1961 (Box 5)
  - Thomas Wolfe Memorial Association, 1949-1954
  - Badge, etc., 1907- 1949
  - Miscellaneous, 1934-1960 (Box 7)
  - YMCA
    - Philippine Islands, 1911-1921
    - China, 1918-1924
    - Foreign countries, 1919-1921
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 28)
- Addresses and Writing Series, 1901-1961, (1 box)
  - 1901-1961 (Box 4)
  - Philippine Islands, 1920
- Printed Material Series, 1891-1969, (6 boxes)
  - Printed Material
    - Philippine Islands, 1916-1924 (Box 6)
    - YMCA, U.S. and territories, 1891-1918
    - YMCA, U.S. and territories, 1919-1936 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1894-1933 (Box 11)
  - Clippings
    - Great Smoky Mountains National Park (Box 10)
      - Acquisitions, 1930-1937
      - Roads, 1930-1937
      - Park movement, 1925-1939
    - Western North Carolina, 1924-1952 (Box 12)
    - Appalachian Mountains, Fauna, 1926-1939 (Box 13)
    - Appalachian Mountains, Flora, 1926-1939
    - Cherokee Indians and other tribes, 1925-1955
    - Horace Kephart, 1927-1936
    - George Masa, 1933
    - Philippine Islands, 1919-1964
    - Miscellaneous, 1903-1969
- Pictures Series, 1906-1930s, (3 boxes)
  - Philippine Islands (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous
  - Albums from Mexico (Box 15)
  - Black Hills Trips, 1914
  - Brookville YMCA Hike, 1907
  - Peyton Album, ca. 1906-1907, (2 folders)
  - Philippine Islands (Box 16)
  - Photograph Albums I and II, 1930s
- Volumes Series, 1857-1940s, (8 boxes)
  - William C. Coleman's Bingham military scrapbook, 1924 (Box 17)
  - Zebulon Baird Vauce's birthplace scrapbook
  - George W. McCoy's Smoky Mountains scrapbook and bibliography (Box 18)
  - George W. McCoy's scrapbook on Great Smoky Mountains National Park Museum
  - Folksongs (Box 19-20)
  - Harry Love's Philippine Island scrapbook (Box 21)
  - Scrapbook, 1928(?)-1938
  - Poems of M. Y. Jarkett of Hillsboro, N.C., 1932 (Box 22)
  - Law school lectures of Chief Justice Richmond Mumford Pearson, 1857
  - Flora of Great Smokies scrapbook
  - The Ladder, 1919-1920
  - YMCA, Philippine Islands
  - Miscellaneous (Box 23)
  - Writings of Lola (Love) McCoy (Box 24)
  - Scrapbook of Lola (Love) McCoy
  - Diary of Wythe M. Peyton, 1908 Mar.-Aug.
  - Harry W. Love's scrapbook, ca. 1920s-1940s
- Frelinghuysen, Southwick Division Series, 1799-1966, (3 boxes)
  - Information Folder (Box 25)
  - Legal papers, 1799-1913
  - Genealogy, 1930
  - Clippings, 1861-1950
  - Miscellaneous, 1906-1925
  - Pictures
  - Family Division (Box 26)
    - Volumes, 1851-1916
    - Correspondence, 1854, 1966 (Box 27)
- Correspondence Series, 1868-1970 and undated, (17 boxes)
  - 1868-1911 (Box 30)
  - 1912-1914 June (Box 31)
  - 1914 July-1915 May (Box 32)
  - 1915 June-Dec. and undated (Box 33)
  - 1916-1918 (Box 34)
  - 1919 (Box 35)
  - 1920 Jan.-June (Box 36)
  - 1920 July-Dec. (Box 37)
  - 1921 Jan.-June (Box 38)
  - 1921 July-Dec. (Box 39)
  - 1922 (Box 40)
  - 1923-1924 (Box 41)
  - 1925-1934 (Box 42)
  - 1935-1937 (Box 43)
  - 1938-1953 (Box 44)
  - 1954-1958 (Box 45)
  - 1959-1970 (Box 46)
- Additional Papers, (1 box)
  - 1986 Accession (Box 1)
- Oversize Materials, (2 oversize folders)
  Consists of blueprints; black and white group photographs; clippings; maps; payrolls; and posters for the Mt. Mitchell Association of Arts and Sciences.